preliminary Guide to the Center for Career Education and Workshops records, 1962-1990 RG0121
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Center for Career Education and Workshops records
1962-1990
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Center for Career Education
RG0121
12 Linear Feet
The materials in this collection consist of Continuing Education for Women Program publications and correspondence; Publication samples, advertisements, and press clippings; Continuing Education for Women Program brochures, articles, history, course schedules, and programs; Legal Assistant Program special events and office files; and American Bar Association annual reports and correspondence related to the Legal Assistant Program.
Restrictions on Access
Series 4 and 5 are closed to research for 25 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition data is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Center for Career Education provides a series of professional certificate programs which help students develop skills and build credentials to meet the demands of an increasingly complex and competitive work environment. A variety of computer and technology classes are offered to those interested in continuing their career education. Much of this collection relates to the Continuing Education for Women program.
Collection Scope and Content
Tha materials in this collection consist of Continuing Education for Women Program publications and correspondence; Publication samples, advertisements, and press clippings; Continuing Education for Women Program brochures, articles, history, course schedules, and programs; Legal Assistant Program special events and office files; and American Bar Association annual reports and correspondence related to the Legal Assistant Program.
Collection Organization
Organized into five series: Continuing Education for Women Program publications and correspondence; Publication samples, advertisements, and press clippings; Continuing Education for Women Program brochures, articles, history, course schedules, and programs; Legal Assistant Program special events and office files; and American Bar Association annual reports and correspondence related to the Legal Assistant Program.
Washington (D.C.); Continuing Education for Women Program; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); Legal Assistant Program; Computers; Technology; Careers; Employment; American Bar Association; George Washington University
- Continuing Education for Women Program publications and correspondence, 1962-1973; RG0121 Series 1; 0.5 Linear foot
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains publications, brochures, new horizon newsletter, correspondence reated to Continuing Education for Women Program. The materials range in date from 1962-73.
  Formerly ACC#42
  This series has a paper container list in the reading room, please ask staff for assistance.
- Publication samples, advertisements, and press clippings, 1963-1984; RG0121 Series 2; 3 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 1)
  This series consists of publication samples, advertisements, press clippings. The materials range in date from 1963-84.
  Formerly ACC#113
- Continuing Education for Women Program brochures, articles, history, course schedules, and programs, 1965-1990; RG0121 Series 3; 1 Linear foot (Box 1, Box 2)
  This series contains brochures, articles, paper by Ruth Osborn on history of program, course schedules, career oriented programs related to the Continuing Education for Women Program. The materials range in date from 1965-90.
  Formerly ACC#907
  - Paper entitled "Continuing Education for Women", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    By Ruth H. Osborn, Director of the Program (2 copies)
  - Continuing Education for Women brochure, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    2 copies
  - Articles, clippings, etc., 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Staff - Ruth Osborn and Abbie Smith, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Developing New Horizons for Women Program, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Course Flyers, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Non-Credit Courses, 1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Course Schedules, 1966-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Course Schedules, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Course Schedules, 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Administrative Manager Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Association Executive Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Counseling Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Employee Benefit Specialist Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Fund-Raising Administrator Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Information Systems Specialism Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Landscape Design Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Legal Assistant Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Management Certificate Programs (General Brochure), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Management Specialist Programs (General Brochure), undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: On-Site Programs and Workshops, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Professional Consultant Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Professional Development Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Public Relations Professional Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Publication Specialist Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Supervisory Specialist Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Test Review Courses (LSAT), undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Career-Oriented Programs: Washington Representative Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Legal Assistant Program special events and office files, 1973-1988; RG0121 Series 4; 3 Linear feet
  This series consists of special events and office files related to the Legal Asistant Program. The materials range in date from 1973-88.
  Formerly ACC#56; formerly RG16.3.5
  - Career Night, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Folders #1-21
  - Specialty Flyers, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Folder #22
  - Job Search/ Job Hunting info, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Folders #23-24
  - Workshops and Seminars offered, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Topics covered: labor law (25-27); complex litigation; Washington rep.; computers; legal writing; tax; government contracts; bankruptcy; environmental, folders #25-51
  - Student Evaluations, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Folder #52
  - Study for VA Bar, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Folder #53
  - Testing Schedule, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Folder #54
  - Advisory Board, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Meeting minutes and reports, folders #55-64
  - Administrative Archives, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Contains class lists, flyers, book lists, form letters, tuition information, workshops, etc., folders #65-72
  - Administrative Archives, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Folders #1-3
  - LAP Running Newsletter, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Folder #4
  - T.V. & Radio Appearances File, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Folder #5
  - ABA Evalution, 1978 ca. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Quinnipiac College, Folder #6
  - ABA Visitation Team, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Wesley Collge, DE, Folder #7
  - Admission Requirement LSAT, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Folder #8
  - Brochures, GWU LAP, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Incomplete, folder #9
  - District Court Career Days, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Folder #10
  - Employer Survey, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Folder #11
  - Employment Workshops, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Folder #12
  - Employment Workshop, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Folder #13
  - Faculty Luncheon and Meeting, 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Meeting minutes, folders #14-23
  - Program Survey Questionaires, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Folder #24
  - Printing, Brochure, Promotion Materials, 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Folders #25-27
  - Recommendation Letter Form, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Folder #28
  - Nu Epsilon Delta, inc, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Miscellaneous, folder #29
  - LAP and GWU T.V., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Folder #30
  - Grading Policy for courses (certificate), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Folder #31
  - Graduate Questionare, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Folder #32
  - Confirmations (registration) for Classes, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Includes books used and instructors, folders #33-38
  - On-site course development, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Folder #39
  - Summer intensive marketing, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Folder #40
  - Legal Economics article by Carol Dietrich, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Carol Dietrich (director 1984-1989), folder #41
  - Enrollment Agreements & Student Handbook, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Folder #42
  - Tuition Benefits Policy Statement, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Folder #43
  - HEW Vietnamese Lawyers' Grant, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Folder #44
  - Loans/Financial Aid Information, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Folder #45
  - LAP Administrative File, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Folder #46
  - LAP No. VA Class Legal Research and Writing, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Folder #47
  - ABA Workshop: Working with Legal Assistants, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Folder #48
  - Department of Justice, Bureau of Prison Proposal, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Folder #49
  - Recruitment Day, 1988, 1987, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Folders #50-51
  - Employment Workshop, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Miscellaneous, folders #52-54
- Legal Assistant Program, 1972-1988; RG0121 Series 5; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of American Bar Association annual reports and correspondence related to the Legal Assistant Program. The materials range in date from 1972-88.
  Formerly ACC#83; formerly RG16.3.5
  - American Bar Association reports, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Bar Association correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Bar Association application and correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Bar Association evaluation visit for approval, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Bar Association annual report, 08/26/1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Bar Association annual report, 08/31/1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Bar Association annual report, 08/31/1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Bar Association annual report, 08/29/1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Bar Association application for re-approval, 01/1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Bar Association re-approval, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Bar Association re-approval evaluation report, 11/23/1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Bar Association re-approval awarded, 08/1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Bar Association annual report, 08/23/1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Bar Association annual report, 01/05/1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    1983 report
  - American Bar Association annual report, 08/30/1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    1984 report
  - American Bar Association annual report, 08/27/1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    1985 report
  - Marketing and publication copies for 1986 self-evaluation report for reapproval (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ABA reapplication self-study, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    With 1988 updates, attachments to 1986 reapproval application, attachments to annual report (Sept. 1988)
  - ABA annual report for 1986 and 1988, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    File copy with marketing originals
  - Advisory board meeting reports, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)